Savkin Nikita

Front-end Developer

% +7(906)041-42-85

□ no.colour.you.like@gmail.com

no-colour-you-like.github.io

im linkedin.com/in/nikitasavkin

Skills

Programming languages

JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML5, CSS (SASS, SCSS)

Libraries & Frameworks

React. Redux

Additional

Git, GitHub, Gulp, NPM, BEM, Responsive design, Debugging

Projects

E-commerce store

Website for a store that sells plants.

React | Redux | Firebase https://no-colour-youlike.github.io/plants-e-commerce

Cryptocurrency Tracker

Tracking cryptocurrency in real time.

JavaScript | API | Chart.js

https://no-colour-youlike.github.io/Crypto

Movies navigation

Navigation with popular movie lists.

JavaScript | API

https://no-colour-youlike.github.io/Movies

Launcher Inc

Website about a rocket engine testing company.

HTML | CSS(SASS) | JS https://no-colour-youlike.github.io/Launcher

Languages

Russian – Native English – Pre-intermediate

Soft Skills

Critical thinking

Adaptability and Flexibility

Teamwork

Profile

I'm a passionate and detail-oriented Front-End Developer. I use my knowledge to create user-friendly web applications for various tasks. I care a lot about the quality of the code and what I create. I have experience in creating responsive websites and web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React. I can assure that I can be a useful member of the company.

Experience

Front-end Developer (Personal websites & web applications)

March 2020 - Present

- Developed and maintained code for client websites primarily using HTML, CSS (SASS) and JavaScript;
- Manually tested sites in various browsers and mobile devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility and responsiveness;
- Wrote modern, performant, maintainable code for websites and web applications.

Achievements: engineered and implemented five adaptive websites, five JavaScript applications and e-commerce project using React.

Assistant cameraman @ TV Centre

September 2019 – June 2021

- Assistance to the cameraman in video recording news stories, sound recording, lighting installation.

Achievements: video recording of news with the participation of the mayor of Moscow, video recording special reports.

Store Manager @ GAP

September 2016 – September 2019

 Control of store activities, accountability, selection and training of employee, control and management of personnel, interaction with customers.

Achievements: recruited and trained 20 employees, increased customer loyalty after controversial situations.

2

Education

The Complete JavaScript Course (Jonas Schmedtmann),

Complete React Developer Course (Andrei Neagoie)

2020 - 2021 // Moscow

Direction: Front-End Development

Moscow State University of Mechanical Engineering

2012 - 2016 // Moscow

Degree: Bachelor's Degree in Management